Toronto, ON +1-(905)-781-6924 ananthac@ocadu.ca

N Anantha Purushothama ²⁴ Chickanayakanahalli

rewritablehere.github.io/folio/

Professional Summary

Senior UX Design Consultant with over nine years of experience in shipping digital products in the IT and ITES industry. My core competency includes *Problem Solving* and translating a consistent brand language across various touch-points while liaising between product development, marketing and end users.

Work Experience

DATES POSITION April 2019 - Nov 2021

RESPONSIBILITIES Advanced User Experience Designer

Create User Experience strategy and artefacts for Honeywell

Airports Business Projects

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS

Honeywell Technology Solutions Lab Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, India

TYPE OF BUSINESS Home & Building Technology

DATES August 2014 - March 2019

POSITION Design Consultant

RESPONSIBILITIES Worked alongside with business analysts, technology architects

to design products and enterprise applications for domains such

as Banking, Insurance, Investment, Tourism, Consumer

Packaged Goods and Manufacturing

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS Mindtree Ltd., Bangalore, India.

TYPE OF BUSINESS Digital Transformation and Technology Service

DATES June 2013 - July 2014

POSITION User Experience Designer

RESPONSIBILITIES Designing turnkey web/mobile software applications

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS Ideus Concepts Information Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Goa, India

TYPE OF BUSINESS Design + Technology Services

DATES November 2012 - May 2013

POSITION Freelance Ux Designer

RESPONSIBILITIES Designed Application flows for a Networking platform for Health

Professionals and an E-commerce portal for fashion products

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS R. K. Enterprises, Pune, India.

TYPE OF BUSINESS Startup

DATES August 2011 - September 2012

POSITION User Interface Designer

RESPONSIBILITIES Designed Web UI for legacy Symantec Product NetBackup

Appliance

EMPLOYER / ADDRESS Symantec Software India Pvt. Ltd., Pune, India.

TYPE OF BUSINESS Software Security and Backup Solutions

Education and Training

DATES September 2021 - Present

QUALIFICATION AWARDED Master of Design (Pursuing)

PRINCIPAL STUDIES Digital Futures

INSTITUTION OCAD University, Canada.

DATES July 2009 - July 2011

QUALIFICATION AWARDED Master of Design

PRINCIPAL STUDIES Interaction Design

Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, India.

DATES September 2003 - July 2009

QUALIFICATION AWARDED Bachelor of Architecture

PRINCIPAL STUDIES Architectural Design

INSTITUTION Bangalore University, India

Skills and Competences

LANGUAGE(S) SPOKEN English, Kannada, Hindi

SOCIAL SKILLS
AND COMPETENCES

- Volunteered/organised international conferences 'In a planet of our own' & 'Designing for Children', 'India HCl 2010' at Industrial Design Centre, IIT Bombay.
- Volunteered/organised conference of Indian Institute of Architects – National Convention'08, Bengaluru
- Secured first place consecutively at intra-departmental design competition in 2006 & 2007.
- Took part in many NASA (national architecture students body) and won Zonal NASA design competitions of 2005 & 2006.

ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS
AND COMPETENCES

Achievements in my previous organisation, Mindtree:

- Awarded Outstanding Performer of the Year 2017-18
- Awarded 7 times as an **A-team** player in various projects.

ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

- Awarded **Hats Off** for achieving extraordinary results in presales pitches and a second time for a commendable user friendly-ness design solution provided for a project of a US based Mass Media Company.
- Awarded **Master Mind** for expert thinking and achieving client satisfaction for a project in the visa services domain.
- Awarded twice for being **Unstoppable**, once for displaying execution excellence for the UX course for my organisation and the other for a project with an US based Insurance firm.

COMPUTER SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

Sketching, Storyboarding, Storytelling, Card sorting, Information Design and Architecture, User Journey Mapping, Visualising Persona Scenarios, Contextual Inquiry, Eye-tracking (basics), Physical Computing and Usability Testing,

Affinity Mapping, Wire-framing, Visual Design and authoring Style Guides.

Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, Sketch, Axure RP, Xmind, HTML/CSS/JS Beginner, Processing, P5JS, Arduino

PUBLICATIONS / PATENTS

Applied for a User Interface Design Patent with my previous employer Honeywell for a Lean Dashboard HMI for Gates Operating System for Airports in Nov 2019. (Yet to be granted)